《破釜沉舟》前情提要
我是郑立  中华人民共和国特使
I'm Zheng Li, special envoy from the People's Republic of China.
我们是你强有力的同盟
As an ally, we are very powerful.
长官  结成联盟吗
An alliance, sir?
政府就是要饿死我们
This administration will starve us out.
你们的补给48小时内送到
You'll have your supplies in 48 hours.
这是白宫方面不想让任何人知道的内容
This is what the White House doesn't want anyone else to see.
一群很有权势的人正在策划一场政变
There are powerful people organizing a coup d'etat.
她肯定被带去了什么地方  我要去找她
They've taken her somewhere, and I'm gonna find her.
山姆
Sam.
你和我一起会不安全
If you're with me, you're not safe.
-我不在乎  -我知道  可我在乎
- I don't care. - Yeah, I know. I do.
山姆
Sam！
克里斯蒂
Christine！
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
美剧字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：萌Su   笨熊猫   lwf5780   圈圈
翻译：竹子  我不是青椒   wdjmhs
校对：米苏  君君  油炸电风扇
时间轴：JimmyBeck  Cherry
后期：zzzyusa   总监：渔夫
720p.WEB-DL 时间轴：Pale_Cheung
你那边情况怎么样  上尉
What's your status, lieutenant?
金已经完成了焊接修理工作
King has completed the weld repairs.
初步修复测试成功
First repair test positive.
正准备进行深潜测试
We're about to conduct the deep dive test.
推迟测试任务  尽快返回港口
It'll have to wait. I need you back in port ASAP.
长官
Sir?
中方的供给船正朝我方驶来  无人护航
The Chinese supply ship is headed towards us unescorted.
美方已经派了一艘驱逐舰前来拦截
The U.S. has sent a destroyer to intercept.
他们是不会让供给船靠岸的
They're not gonna let her reach our shores.
还有  暴风雨即将袭来
Also, there's a storm bearing down.
风力强度已经达到台风级别
Winds approaching typhoon strength.
岛上的情况不容乐观
The situation on the island has grown critical.
我们必须保证供给船的安全
We need that supply ship to make it through.
我要你在台风到来之前返回港口
I need you in before it hits
这样我才能控制潜艇
so I can take command of the boat.
遵命  长官
Aye aye, sir.
警告全员  这是一次战斗巡逻任务
Alert the crew. This will be a combat patrol mission.
全速前进  上尉
All ahead flank, lieutenant.
收到  全速前进  科罗拉多完毕
Ahead flank, aye.  Colorado out.
我觉得你可能会在这儿
I thought I might find you here.
是吗
Yeah.
山姆  你妻子的事我感到很遗憾
Sam, I'm very sorry for your wife.
如果需要我帮忙的话
If I can do anything...
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know what to say.
怎么了
What is it?
你以为你是我什么人
Who do you think you are to me?
我想和你做朋友
I'm trying to be your friend.
做朋友吗
You want to be friends?
你觉得我们应该怎么样  朋友
What do you think we should do, friend?
你是想...
You wanna...
跟我上床
you want to jump in the sack?
以性爱抚平我内心的伤痛吗
You want to screw the pain away?
你是那么想的吗
Is that what you want to do?
好吧  我明白你的意思了
Okay. Uh, I understand.
我以为我们的关系没有那么肤浅
I think there is a bit more between us than that.
让我们都坦诚相对吧
Let's just be honest right now,
我现在只想实话实说
'cause that's all I can deal with.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
即使是在此地  此刻
Even right here, right now,
我们之间
What's going on between us,
我对朋友可没这种感觉
I promise you, this is not how I feel about my friends.
我不喜欢自己这样子  你明白吗
And I hate myself for it. You get it?
你真的想做我的朋友吗
So you want to be my friend really?
真的吗
Really?
那就让我一个人静静
Then you gotta leave me alone.
好的
Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
放心  我不会再来烦你
And, yes, I'll leave you alone.
月亮
Lunar
七
Seven
十九
Nineteen
四
Four
十一
Eleven
海豚
Dolphin
九
Nine
你是否重新获得了发射钥匙
没有
六十
Sixty
七
Seven
八
Eight.
权限无效  无权继续使用此频道
该死
Damn it.
查普林已与中方结盟
准备与驱逐舰交锋  请求指示
卡吕普索
Calypso.
三十七
Thirty seven.
立即杀死马库斯・查普林
你要去哪儿吗
You going somewhere?
我派琼斯去找你了
I sent Jones to find you.
知道了
Yeah.
想谈谈吗
You want to talk about it?
不想
No.
听着  山姆  我知道你现在的感受
Look, Sam, I know what you're going through.
我也经历过  我知道...
I've been there. I know that--
艇长  请别...
Captain, please....
我知道找到正确的途径释放悲伤
I know that finding the right way to grieve
是很难的
is never easy.
但你不必一个人硬抗
But you do not have to do this alone.
当年你也在我身边陪着我
God knows you were there for me.
政府派了一艘驱逐舰
The administration has sent a destroyer
拦截中国的供给船
to intercept the Chinese supply ship.
我要指挥科罗拉多号进行干预作战
I'm taking the "Colorado" out to intervene.
士兵们正在挨饿  大家都撑不住了
Our people are starving. Everyone's falling apart.
我们需要那艘船上的供给品
We need the food and supplies on that ship.
我们在干什么  艇长
What are we doing here, captain?
我们在干什么  我以为我们是要
What are we doing? I thought we were supposed to be
揭发真相  然后回家去
getting to the truth so we could all get home.
那不才是我们该干的事情吗
Isn't that what we're supposed to be doing?
我们得先活下去
We have to survive first.
怎么活  和中国结盟吗
How, by aligning with the Chinese?
那怎么能让我们回家
How does that get us home?
你觉得还有别的选择吗  副艇长
You see any other options, X.O.?
我们现在处在孤立无援的状态
There's not a whole bunch of folks stepping up to take our side.
什么时候我们也开始卑躬屈膝了  长官
I didn't realize we had our hat in hand, sir.
我是绝对不会让岛民
I will not allow the people of this island
和士兵们挨饿的
and our people to starve.
我要是不参与这件事  我妻子也不会死
I didn't do this, my wife didn't die,
你去做你的三流香蕉国国王吧
so you could become king of some third-rate Banana Republic.
你被革职了  指挥官
You're relieved, commander.
我早决定走了  艇长
I'm way ahead of you, captain.
你们都疯了吗
Have you all lost your minds?
在美利坚合众国策划一场政变
A coup d'etat in the United States of America,
你们说得是这个意思吗
that is what you're talking about, correct?
议长先生  如果我们不采取行动
Mr. Speaker, if we don't act,
世上就不会再有美利坚合众国了
there won't be a United States of America.
这是第188号行政令
This is Executive Order 188,
由总统亲自签发
issued by the president,
命令一队海豹突击队员
directing a team of Navy SEALs
暗杀奥斯卡・尼尔斯博士
to assassinate Dr. Oscar Nils,
联合国派遣到巴基斯坦的武器核查员
the U.N. Weapons inspector in Pakistan.
核实了吗
This has been verified?
那份命令是真实有效的
That is an authentic order, sir.
我是说  确定命令被执行了吗
No, has it been verified that the order was carried out?
监察员已经死了
The inspector is dead.
是巴基斯坦人干的
At the hands of the Pakistanis.
不  康尼  是我们干的
No, Connie. We did it.
我们杀了他
We killed him.
我们的海豹突击队员
Our SEALs.
上将  你应该在牢里
You're supposed to be in jail, admiral.
在外人的眼里  我是在牢里
As far as anyone knows, I am.
我还是有几个小人物朋友的
I just have a few friends in low places.
听着  我们得马上离开这里
Okay. We all need to walk outta here this very second,
以免谁说了什么不可挽回的话
before somebody says something they're gonna regret.
议长先生  你知道我通常不介意
Mr. Speaker, you know I'm not generally squeamish
以武力先下手为强
about the preemptive use of force.
我本人也曾亲自
In fact, I've personally jammed
阻止了你几项拨款法案的通过
quite a few appropriation bills past you in my time.
政治上来说  我可以说
And since politically, I straddle a line
匈奴帝国领袖  凶残野蛮  被认为是文明社会的公敌
比匈奴王阿提拉强不了多少
just slightly to the left of Attila the Hun,
所以相信我
you will believe me when I say,
我参与这件事不是为了搞垮
I did not get into this in order to take down
我最好的  也是唯一的付款客户
my best and only paying customer.
这是巴里・霍普军士
This is Petty Officer Barry Hopper,
就是这个海豹突击队员收到命令
the Navy SEAL who received orders
用便携核弹栽赃
to plant evidence of suitcase nukes
并暗杀了那个认定巴基斯坦没有核武器的
and to assassinate the nuclear inspector who had determined
武器核查员
that there were no such devices in Pakistan.
这段视频
And this is him
记录了他执行命令
carrying out those orders,
而行动之后  便发生了核弹袭击
which were then followed by a nuclear first strike.
阿什兰德上将  议长先生
General Ashland, Mr. Speaker,
你们都熟悉我的为人
you both know me.
我通常真的只顾自己  不管他人死活
I really don't care about anyone other than myself.
如果连我都感到义愤填膺
So if this got me pissed off,
那你们这些道德高尚  为人民服务的人
what should it do to upstanding, civic-minded men
又做何感想
such as yourselves?
你派了艘没有护卫的船
You're sending me a ship unescorted?
船上有我们说好的供给
The supplies we promised.
我警告过你美国对此会有激进的反应
I warned you the U.S. response would be aggressive.
如果中国不打算保护自己的船只
Now if China isn't willing to defend its vessel,
我要你有什么用
why do I need you?
你之前打算对自己国家...
Well, you were willing to take on your country--
你想错了
You misunderstand me.
我冒着无法回国的危险
I didn't join with you at great cost
和你联手  为的可不是
to any hopes I have of ever going home
换取你派来一艘
so that you could send me a ship
连岸都靠不上的船
with little chance of ever reaching my shores.
你想让我们怎么样
What would you have my country do?
有点用最好
Be of use to me.
言而有信  保卫你们自己的船只
Back up your words and protect your own vessel.
并跟美国宣战
And start a war with the U.S.?
我们愿意帮忙  艇长  但也要有限度
We're willing to help, captain, but there are limits.
如果你们自己都不打算救自己
And why should we help you more than
我们为什么还要帮忙
you're willing to help yourself?
如果美国强迫其停船或者将其击沉
If the U.S. stops this ship, maybe sinks it,
那美国就成了国际舞台上的入侵者
it becomes the aggressor on the international stage.
如果美国让船只通过
If it lets it through,
中国就成了人道主义者
China becomes a great humanitarian.
中国也是赢家
And it also wins.
你算计得很好
You played this very well.
谢谢
Thank you.
只是你什么也没给我
Except that you've given me nothing.
不对
Untrue.
即便面临你国的威胁
Even in the face of threats from your nation,
我依然提供了食物供给
I offer you food and aid.
还有哪个国家敢这么干
What other nation would even dare?
我为你提供了在岛上生存的机会
Life on this island is what I offer you.
你对外面的情况的处理  就是对我的回报
What happens out there is what you give me in return.
你想要与美国正面冲突
You want a confrontation with the U.S.?
多少年来  美国都被看成
For how many years has the U.S. been seen
世界超级霸权的守护者
as the guardian superpower of the world,
理性的中心
the rational center?
你们政府不能再令人信服地
Your administration can no longer claim that role
扮演这个角色
with any credibility.
听清楚了
Please understand me.
我不会成为你们斗争的棋子
I won't be a proxy in your fight.
带着核武器库的棋子
A proxy with a nuclear arsenal.
现在的情况还不是最糟的
There are worse things to be.
小心点  大使先生
Be careful, Mr. Ambassador.
你现在玩的游戏依然很危险
There's still a very dangerous game you're playing.
我与美国过招
I've swapped chess pieces with the U.S.
不是一天两天了  艇长
for many years now, captain.
我说的不是美国
I'm not talking about the U.S.
各长官做好准备
Officer on deck.
稍息
At ease.
我是查普林  我的车呢
This is Chaplin. Where's my transport?
艇长  科罗拉多号还有20分钟入港
Captain, the Colorado Is still 20 minutes from port.
他们一到我们就派辆吉普过去
We'll send a jeep for you as soon as they're close.
收到
Copy that.
好大的雨
It's crazy out there.
你跑哪去了
Where you coming from?
汽艇出了点问题
There was, uh, some trouble with the launch.
我搞定了
I took care of it.
有没有什么能暖暖身子的
You got anything back there to warm me up?
就是这里
Right there.
我们的任务改变了
There's where our mission parameters changed.
我接到命令要栽赃
I was ordered to plant evidence
以说明巴基斯坦对美国造成
that Pakistan posed an imminent nuclear threat
可预见的核威胁
to the United States.
我执行了命令
I carried out that order.
你们想让我怎么办
What do you want me to do?
明天
Tomorrow
正午12点
at 1200 hours,
麦克奈尔堡的陆军分队
Army units out of Fort McNair
将在麦克沃伊将军的指挥下
under the command of General Macavoy,
封锁全城
will shut the city down--
所有桥梁和隧道都不许出入
all bridges, tunnels, no one in or out.
同时  在阿什兰德将军指挥下
At the same time, the EADS, under General Ashland,
国会山上空将会建立禁飞区
will enforce a no-fly zone over the capitol.
一旦这两项目标达成
And once those two objectives have been met,
里德将军手下的海军陆战队
A marine force recon contingent under General Reid
将占领白宫
will take the White House.
他们会把总统和副总统
And there they will place the president
逮捕起来
and the vice president under arrest.
与此同时  议长先生
Now, Mr. Speaker,
你会召开参众两院联席会议
you will have already called a joint session of Congress,
阐明针对本届政府的弹劾案
and there you will outline the case against the administration
作为继任总统顺序表里的第三顺位
and announce that you, as third in the line of succession,
你将就任总统一职
are assuming the presidency.
副艇长怎么样了
How's the X.O. doing?
痛失所爱的感觉一定无法想象
Must be horrible to lose someone you love.
我听到儿子死讯的时候还在海上
I was at sea when I heard
我第一次作为艇长出航
my first command.
一架直升机将我从亚得里亚海里接走
A helicopter plucked me out of the Adriatic.
我在塞浦路斯找了一辆车
I took a transport from Cyprus.
到了那里  我第一眼见到的
And the first thing I saw when I got there
是我的两个儿子
were my two boys.
现在
Now...
我也参加过战斗
I've been in combat.
但是我从未在任何人的眼里看到过
But I've never seen fear in anyone's eyes
那天我儿子们眼里的恐惧
like I saw in the eyes of my sons that day.
因为他们明白
'cause they knew.
还有
So...
我和妻子在一起最久的一段时间
My wife's illness was the longest continuous period of time
就是她患病的那段时间
that we ever spent together.
而事实是
And the truth is,
我更像是娶了海军  而不是娶了她
I was more married to the navy than I ever was to her.
我更像是我手下的好父亲
I was a better father to the men under my command
而不是我儿子们的好父亲
than I was to my own sons.
上天很眷顾我
I was given a blessing,
但我
But was...
蠢到根本没有意识到这一点
too foolish to fully know what it was.
我没有孩子  所以
I don't have any kids so...
或许我不知道我在说些什么  不过
Maybe I don't know what I'm talking about, but...
如果你听到我在讨论某人
If you heard me talk about someone
就像你刚在讨论你自己那样
the way that you just talked about yourself,
你一定会说我是个大八婆的
You would think that I was the biggest bitch walking.
我当时不用留在海上
I didn't have to stay at sea.
但是我想当艇长
But I wanted to make captain.
我的眼睛是雪亮的
My eyes were open.
我很清楚我是在干什么
I knew exactly what I was doing.
现在也一样
Just like I know now.
我的眼睛是雪亮的
My eyes are open.
长官
Sir.
最后一辆汽艇准备离港了
The last launch is ready to depart.
吉普车在待命
Jeep's waiting.
我们该走了
That's our ride.
谢谢
Thanks.
你说有事要和我商量
You said there was something you needed to discuss.
你是个漂亮女人  索菲
You're a beautiful woman, Sophie.
在巴黎顶尖的学校接受的教育
Been educated in the finest Parisian schools.
习惯于高品质的生活
You're accustomed to the finer things,
但你却把自己放逐到这座岛上
yet you maroon yourself on this island
一个鸟不拉屎的地方
in the middle of nowhere.
我的工作就在这里
This is where my work is.
是你选择了在这里工作
This is where you choose your work to be.
你是在逃避生活
You're running away from life.
我不想知道你是在逃避什么样的痛苦
I don't propose to know what pain it is you are running from,
但你人在这里
but here you are.
现在你又在浪费你的生命
And now you are wasting yourself,
痴望着已婚的海军军官
mooning over this married naval officer.
你不知道自己在说些什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
我了解你
I know you.
我关心你
I care for you,
远超你所想象
very deeply, more than you know.
而且我知道你关心这座岛
And I know you care for this island.
你担心着这座岛会变成什么样子
And you worry about what will become of it.
打开它
Open it.
我相信  最伟大的礼物  便是真相
I believe the greatest gift is the gift of truth.
-朱利安  -停  别说了
- Julian. - stop, please.
我另外雇了一个人做土壤测试
I had someone else run the soil test.
这座岛富含稀土元素
This island is worth a fortune in rare earth elements.
你对我撒了谎  索菲
You lied to me, Sophie.
朱利安  如果你开采这些矿物
Julian, if you exploit those minerals,
岛上你所珍爱的一切都会被破坏
everything you love about this island will be destroyed.
这里是我的家
This is my home.
你为什么会认为我会破坏这座岛
What makes you think I would destroy this island?
情况会改变的
Look, the situation will change.
美国佬会离开
The Americans will leave,
一切都会恢复正常
and things will return to normal.
到那时
And when they do,
你为什么还要住在北约观察站里
why live in the NATO housing
而不是住在海边别墅里
when you can live in a villa on the coast?
我可以提供给你舒适  安全
I can provide for you comfort, security,
机会
opportunity.
朱利安
Oh, Julian.
你看起来好像刚吃了虫子一样
You look as though you just ate a beetle.
别担心  我不是在向你求爱
Don't worry. I'm not talking about love.
我知道你不爱我
I know you don't love me.
那又是为什么
What then?
每个人都有弱点
Every man has a weakness.
你就是我的弱点
You are mine.
我能接受你不爱我
And I accept you where you are.
我提意的是
Thus, what I propose
一种合作关系
is a partnership...
基于相互的感情
based on mutual affection.
我们可以一起照料这座岛
We can take care of this island together.
你可以作为我的良知
You can be my conscience.
而我可以满足你的任何心愿
and I will reward my conscience
作为对你的报答
with whatever her heart desires.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
随着时间推移  或许你会发现
In time, you may find
你对我也有了相同的感觉
that you feel for me the same way I feel for you.
祝你好胃口
Bon appetit.
谢谢
Merci.
不再有任何抱怨
No more public rumbling.
不再有条条框框
No more breaking the rules.
我们解决这个问题
We do this right.
找出我们需要的人  等到时机成熟
Find the men we need, and then when the moment's right,
我们接管
we take over.
为何不直接把他干掉
Why don't we just take him out?
一了百了
Be done with it.
什么  不行 不行
What? No. No, no, no. Hell, no.
我们不能那么做
We are not doing that.
那不是我们的目的
That is not what this is about.
让他活着只能让事情变得更复杂
Well, keeping him alive only makes things more complicated.
你们都想想本・拉登
You all think about Bin Laden.
扣动两下扳机  然后把尸体扔进印度洋
Double tap, dumped in the Indian Ocean.
他就从此人间蒸发了
he's out of sight, out of mind.
华莱士  我们的艇长不是恐怖分子
Wallace, our captain is not a terrorist.
不是吗
No?
那他是什么
Well, what the hell is he?
窃取潜艇  向华府发射核武器
Stealing a sub, launching a nuke at D.C.--
他现在正要因为一船该死的大米
Hell, he's out there right now starting a superpower showdown
挑起超级大国之间的决战
over a boatload of damn rice.
大米  不是...
Rice? No, it's not--
在南卡罗莱纳  我们就管这个叫恐怖分子
In South Carolina, we call that a terrorist.
水手长  你不下命令我们是不会行动的
C.O.B., you know we wouldn't make a move without your go.
但是我们必须考虑
But terminating the captain's command
解除艇长的职务了
may be an option we have to consider.
大家跟副艇长打声招呼
Everybody, say hello to the X.O.
跟上
Keep up！
快点
Go, go go！
快
Hurry！
我投降行吗
Might I suggest a white flag?
先暂停一下
A temporary parlay
我把脸上身上的泥弄干净行吗
so I can get the mud outta my butt crack?！
我们先找地方避避雨
Let's go get some cover.
声纳员  报告驱逐舰当前位置
Sonar, report on the destroyer's position.
报告长官  美国帕特里克-劳伦斯号
It's the U.S.S. "Patrick Lawrence," Sir.
方位2-2-9度  距离18000码
Bearing 2-2-9, range 1 8,000 yards.
好
Very well.
凯希尔上尉
Lieutenant Cahill,
联系驱逐舰舰长
get the destroyer's captain on the line.
是  长官
Aye aye, sir.
帕特里克-劳伦斯号
U.S.S. "Patrick Lawrence,"
这里是科罗拉多号
this is the U.S.S. "Colorado."
是否收到  完毕
How copy? Over.
这里是帕特里克-劳伦斯号
This is the U.S.S. "Patrick Lawrence."
我是埃文・索恩舰长
Captain Evan Thorn.
很高兴再次和你通话  艇长
It's good to speak with you again, captain.
我们认识吗  舰长
Do we know each other, captain?
在安纳波利斯
Annapolis.
想当年我听过你的讲座
I was at a lecture you gave some years back.
讲座的题目是
It was the "Men will do anything
《正义之士所向披靡》
if their cause is just" speech.
你真是个能言善辩的演说家啊  艇长
You are one hell of a public orator, captain.
多谢夸奖
That's very kind of you.
你写的所有战时海军准则我都读过
You know, I've read everything you've ever written on wartime naval code,
虽然现在的情况特殊
and although the circumstances might suggest otherwise,
但我承认  我很崇拜你
I must confess, I'm a bit of a fan.
真是过奖了  我希望我们能找到方法
That's very flattering, and I hope we can find
以和平方式解决我们的冲突
a peaceful solution to our conflict today.
正如你所知  有艘中国商船
As you know, I have a Chinese merchant vessel
要往圣玛丽娜岛运送补给
en route to Sainte Marina carrying supplies
那对我的艇员
vital to the well-being of my crew
和当地居民非常重要
and to the local civilians.
我想提前声明
I want to make it very clear
你方任何阻碍商船的行为
that any action on your part to impede its progress
都将被视为侵略行为
will be taken as an act of aggression
我方会予以反击
and will be met in kind.
侵略
Aggression?
我的驱逐舰和你的核弹对抗吗
Your boomer versus my destroyer?
我们都知道你可以不费吹灰之力
We both know you could blow me out of the water
就把我炸飞
and never even break a sweat.
那你方今天此行的目的
Then shall I regard your presence here today
就只是单纯的合理抗议吗
as nothing more than a respectful protest?
不是  艇长
No, captain.
我接到的命令是拦截补给船只
My orders are to stop that supply ship.
但事情无关军士装备
But this isn't about hardware.
重点是我的信仰
It's about what I believe
还有你的信仰
and what you believe.
最重要的是  我知道你的为人
And most importantly, it's what I know about you.
你觉得你知道我什么
And what is it you think you know about me?
马库斯・查普林是绝对不会向
Marcus Chaplin will never fire
美国海军舰艇开火的
on a U.S. Navy ship, ever.
这是次人道主义救援行动
This is a humanitarian mission,
索恩舰长  我...
captain Thorn, and I--
我不管行动是什么性质
I don't care what kind of mission it is.
在美国政府看来
As far as your government is concerned,
这是中国人在帮助美国的敌人
the Chinese are aiding an enemy of the United States.
这是艘没有任何武器装备的民用船
This is an unarmed civilian vessel.
但是我有命在身
I have my orders.
绝对不能让那艘补给船在圣玛丽娜岛靠岸
That supply ship never gets to Sainte Marina,
完毕
period.
谢帕德上尉  帕特里克-劳伦斯号
Lieutenant Shepard, intercept range
还有多久到达补给船只
of the "Patrick Lawrence" to the supply ship?
大约22分钟  长官
He'll be on her in approximately 22 minutes, sir.
索恩舰长  你方有20分钟的时间掉头
Captain Thorn, you have 20 minutes to turn your ship around
否则我方将进行攻击  科罗拉多号完毕
or prepare to receive fire, period. "Colorado" out.
你要继续那样的话  会晕倒的
You keep doing that, you're gonna pass out.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我想下潜艇时  艇长却上来了
I tried to get off when your captain got on,
但是他真是迫不及待要开战
but he wasn't wasting any time in his big rush off to war,
所以我就被关在这里了
so here I am.
他现在真的在考虑
He's seriously thinking about firing
向一艘美国驱逐舰开火
on an American destroyer.
你应该明白  这一刻迟早是要到来的
You had to figure the shooting was gonna start sometime.
如果连这个准备都没有的话
If you're not prepared for that,
那你在这里干什么
what are you doing here?
我认识帕特里克-劳伦斯号上的人
I know people on the "Patrick Lawrence"--
有朋友  水手  跟你我一样的
Friends, sailors, just like you and me.
如果开火的话
If we fire...
这些核弹的有效载荷...
The payload on these mark 48s...
那帕特里克-劳伦斯号上剩下的
There'll be nothing left of the "Patrick Lawrence"
就只有DNA了
but D.N.A.
一招毙命  就是这样设计的
One punch. That's the design.
海军一向不喜欢非致命性武器
The navy's not big on nonlethal options.
怎么了
What?
你们刚才在讨论一场全面的叛变
Your guys back there, they're talking full-blown mutiny.
对  应该是吧
Yeah. Sounds like to me.
他们想用老式的绞刑来处理
They're headed towards a good old-fashioned hanging.
真的准备去谋杀你的老朋友吗
Is that where you are, ready to murder your old friend?
等等
Hold on.
我只是想帮大家
I'm just a bachelorette shopping for
摆脱这件破事
my Mr. Right way out of this suck hole.
你应该还记得
You gotta remember,
他把你放出监狱的时候我也在场
I was there when he released you from the brig.
当时你站在那里
I was there when you stood there,
看着他的眼睛
you looked him right in the eye,
向他保证不会与他为敌
and you promised you wouldn't work against him.
他还向我保证过要把自己
Yeah, and he promised me he was gonna get himself
和我们都弄回家呢
and the rest of us back home.
可结果呢  来了位中国大使
Instead we got a Chinese ambassador in our backyard,
他就为一堆人叫了份"外卖"
and he's ordering takeout for 8,000.
你这是怎么了
What the hell happened to you?
踩到海蜇上了
Stepped on a jellyfish.
也可能是个喷灯
Or a blowtorch.
可能是个喷灯
Or a blowtorch?
你怎么止痛的
How you managing the pain?
别担心
Oh, don't worry about me.
我心里有数  不像某些人
I got my stuff under control, unlike some of us.
什么意思
What does that mean?
那是你的问题  副艇长
That's the problem with you, X.O.
因为你无处可去才加入我们
You joined up because you had nowhere else to go,
又或者你很迷茫
or maybe you were lost,
觉得军队能为你指点迷津
and you thought the military could sort your way out.
你不配称爱国者  起码没发自内心
But you're not a patriot, not at heart.
无论对错都是我的祖国  是吗  水手长
My country, right or wrong, is that you, C.O.B.?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
可你从未想过会被考验
But you never thought you'd be tested.
你只想着晋升
You thought you'd just get your promotions,
养几个小孩  然后颐养天年
raise some rug rats, retire fat.
从未真正考虑过祖国对于你意味着什么
Never have to say what your country really means to you.
如今是时候了  副艇长
But you do now, X.O.
你得下决定
You gotta decide.
长官  我们有个计划
Sir. We have a plan,
能够避免伤亡  至少避免大规模伤亡
a way to avoid bloodshed, or at least too much bloodshed.
说
I'm listening.
我受过弹药训练
I've got munitions training.
能取出鱼雷中
I could rig one of your torpedoes,
百分之80的弹药
remove 80% of the payload.
就算我们被迫开火
So if we're forced to fire,
我们可以予以警告而不炸毁驱逐舰
we can send the Destroyer home in a sling, not a coffin.
时间紧迫  尽快完成
The clock's running down. Get her done.
帕特里克-劳伦斯号即将进入射程
The "Patrick Lawrence" is reaching firing range,
还有六分钟
Six minutes.
动作快点
I won't wait for you.
弹药训练
Munitions training?
一点点
Yeah. A little.
艇长接管指挥台
Captain on the conn.
一级战斗部署
Battle stations.
鱼雷舱  这里是指挥台
Torpedo room, conn.
报告鱼雷改装进度
Report status of torpedo modifications.
金
King.
-进行中  长官  -你还有4分38秒
- In the works, sir. - You have four minutes, 38 seconds.
收到  长官
Roger, sir.
帕特里克-劳伦斯号进入射程
"Patrick Lawrence" Maneuvering into range.
索恩上校  我重复一遍
Captain Thorn, I repeat,
我说到做到
I'm prepared to do what I have to do.
我这是和拒绝对祖国尽忠的
I'm talking to the man who bouna sailor
叛变海军说话呢
for failing to hold salute for the "Arizona".
舰长  话又绕了回来
That's going way back, captain.
不久之前  同样是你
The same man who, a short time ago,
拒绝发射核弹
refused to fire his nuclear missiles
因为指令并非来自正确频道
because he didn't have the proper line of communication.
你不是按规则走的人  艇长
You're not by-the-book, captain.
规则是你订的
You wrote the damn thing.
所以擅自开火
So firing on your own?
不  那是你永远不会
No, that's a line of self-betrayal
逾越的规矩
you're not ever gonna cross.
你最好是有确切把握  舰长
You have to be absolutely sure of that, captain.
我有做好事前准备  所以他们才派我来
I've done my homework. That's why they sent me.
"他们"  你听谁的命令
"They"? Who are you taking orders from?
你自己知道吗
Do you even know?
至少我的工资支票还是美国开的
Last I looked, Uncle Sam was still writing the checks.
如果政府已不是我们的政府
What if our government isn't our government anymore,
而且我的原因很合理呢
and my cause is, in fact, justified?
别跟我扯政治
Don't pull that political head trip with me.
我知道敌人是谁
I know who the enemy is.
问题是  在你人生中  第一次
The problem is, for the first time in your life,
你不知道
you don't.
不  问题是
No, the problem is,
你以为你还是在和以前
you think the man you're talking to
曾经给你做过讲座的人说话
is the same one whose lecture you attended.
他已改变
He's not.
立刻返航  艇长
Turn your ship around, captain.
拒绝
Request denied.
我们在训练期间学过
We've got this drill during Bud's training.
度日如年地躺在冰冷海浪带中
We lay in the ice-cold surf for what seems like forever, nonstop.
日落月升
The Sun goes down, moon comes up,
又日升
Sun comes up again,
我们还在水中  全身僵硬
we're still in the water, arms locked.
感觉就要死了
Feels like you're gonna die.
听起来很有意思
Sounds fun.
不  有意思的是
No, here's the fun part.
他们在岸边桌上放了
They sit coffee and doughnuts on a table
咖啡和甜甜圈  还放了个铃
just in sight of the surf next to a bell.
那样  如果你想离开
That way, when you're ready to quit,
就起身走过去  按铃
you just stand up, walk over to the table, ring the bell--
你们海豹突击队真喜欢讲这故事
You S.E.A.L.S never get tired of telling this story, do you?
-这个吗  -是
- Uh, is that... - Yeah.
千万  别  掉了
Don't... drop...this.
重点是
The point is,
入水前我就能
I could tell who was gonna ring that bell
看出谁会按
before we ever got in the water.
我能看透他们眼神
I could see it in their eyes.
你在说艇长
You're talking about the captain.
他不会  格蕾丝
He's not a bell ringer, Grace.
他能看透这一切掌握结局
He'll see this through to the bitter end.
问题是
The question is--
谢帕德上尉  我需要鱼雷立刻就位
Lieutenant shepard, I need that torpedo now.
快好了  长官
We're close, sir.
确切时间  立刻报告
Exact time? Report now.
两分钟  长官
Two minutes, sir.
给你60秒
You have 60 seconds.
下潜  潜望深度  全速前进三分之一
Dive. Periscope depth. All head one-third.
凯希尔上尉  时间
Lieutenant Cahill, how much time?
帕特里克-劳伦斯号30秒后进入射程
"Patrick Lawrence" will be in firing range in 30 seconds, sir.
我会按命令行事的  艇长
I will carry out my orders, captain.
20秒  长官
20 seconds, sir.
索恩舰长  最后警告
Captain Thorn, this is my final warning.
你想让全世界知道你是个疯狂的人
You want the world to think you're a mad man,
但我知道你不是
but I know you're not.
强行挑战将是致命的错误
Testing that theory would be a fatal mistake.
我就要这么做  准备密集阵近防炮
I am testing it. Prepare phalanx gun.
帕特里克-劳伦斯号火力锁定中国商船
"Patrick lawrence" has a firing solution locked on chinese vessel.
开火
Fire！
帕特里克-劳伦斯号命令中方停船
"Patrick lawrence" ordering Chinese to heave to
否则将集火舷侧
or the next barrage will be broadside.
他要击沉她  长官
He's gonna sink her, sir.
她稳定在航线上  未返航
She's steady on course. She's not turning around.
谢帕德上尉  准备一号二号发射管
Lieutenant Shepard, make tubes one and two fully ready
全部待发
in all respects.
MK48先进能力重型鱼雷
Mark 48 ADCAP war shots.
不  等等
No. Wait.
长官  快好了  就一分钟
Sir, we're close. One more minute.
帕特里克-劳伦斯号已经恢复  长官
"Patrick lawrence" coming around again, sir.
一分钟后补给船只
In one minute, that supply ship
和船上人员都会死掉
and everyone aboard her will be dead.
长官  我们立刻将改进鱼雷放进三号管
Sir, we'll be loading tube three with the modified torpedo momentarily.
一号二号鱼雷发射管  做好一切准备
Make tubes one and two fully ready in all respects.
射击位置为"帕特里克-劳伦斯"号
Firing point procedures on the "Patrick Lawrence,"
一号发射管为主攻  二号替补
Tube one primary, tube two backup.
已就位  长官
Solution ready, sir.
降低桅杆和天线
Lower all masts and antennas.
下潜  深度200英尺
Dive. Make your depth 200 feet.
下潜  俯角5度
Dive. 5-degree down angle.
-射击管道已就位  -一号发射
- We have a firing solution. - Fire one.
不  不要发射
No. Belay that. Do not fire.
混蛋
Oh, son of a bitch！
三号管道的改良鱼雷已就位  长官
Modified torpedo ready in tube three, sir.
改良鱼雷已经可以发射了  长官
The modified torpedo is ready to fire, sir.
三号管道  长官
Tube three, sir.
三号发射
Fire three.
水中发现鱼雷
Torpedo in the water！
船体准备接受冲击
Rig ship for impact.
已经引爆  长官
We have detonation, sir.
一个螺旋桨失灵
Have one screw out of commission.
好像
Sounds like...
就是这样
That's it.
船体还能正常运作
Her hull's holding together.
索恩艇长  如果你现在撤退
Captain Thorn, if you retreat now
你和全体船员都可平安回家
you can get your men back home safely.
你有10秒时间考虑
You have ten seconds.
我敢保证  下一次发射绝对会击沉你
I promise you, the next one will put you at the bottom.
长官
Sir...
他们改变航向了
Contact turning on new heading.
1-3-9方向
1-3-9.
他们撤退了  长官
She's bugging out, sir.
谢帕德上尉  我们谈一下
Lieutenant Shepard, a word.
你违抗了我的命令
You disobeyed my order.
不  长官
No, sir, I--
你延迟了命令的执行
You delayed carrying it out.
是的  长官
Yes, sir, I did.
我坐镇指挥台时  我的命令绝不容违背
When I'm on the conn, my word is law！
我明白了
I understand.
是吗  下次你最好确保这一点
Do you? Because I need to know that next time--
记住我的话  肯定会有下一次的
And mark my words, there will be a next time--
我的命令要予以执行
My orders are to be carried out--
一字不漏地执行  毫不迟疑
My exact orders-- without hesitation.
我知道了  长官
I hear you, sir.
但这里的海域你并不熟悉
But you are sailing in some uncharted waters.
不管你信不信
And believe it or not...
我这样做是为了你
I did this for you.
如果他是对的呢
What if he's right?
显然政府已经彻底失控
Obviously the administration's off the rails.
他们正出卖我们立誓要保护的崇高价值
They're selling out every value you swore to protect.
你想让我遵从上帝的指引吗
You want me to have a come to jesus moment?
可以啊  但你也一样
That's fine. But you, too.
如果他是对的呢
What if he's right?
如果是你选错了阵营呢
What if you're fighting the wrong fight?
外面上演着战斗
Being holed up over here
而我却被困在这里
while the fighting's going on over there,
我决不会接受
that doesn't work for me.
所以你要怎么办  杀了马库斯然后回家吗
So what are you gonna do, kill Marcus to get home?
是这样吗
Is that it?
不会那样的  我不会允许
That's not gonna happen. Not on my watch.
但你必须承认
But you gotta be honest with yourself.
马库斯变了
Marcus is different.
我认识他20年了
I've known him for 20 years,
而现在的马库斯我完全不认识
and Marcus 2.0 is a guy I don't even recognize.
是啊  他确实变了  他在适应
Yeah, you're damn right he is. He's adapting.
他在适应环境啊
He's adapting to his environment.
他在处理目前的状况
He's dealing with the situation.
他那不是适应  是在重建秩序
He's not adapting. He's shaping it.
鞭笞自己的手下  跟中国人串通一气
Flogging his men. He's in bed with the Chinese.
马库斯那样的人守着原则生存
Men like Marcus live by a set of rules.
一旦打破了原则
And when those rules break down,
人也会崩溃
the man breaks down.
那间杂房里的人
Those boys back at the roadhouse,
他们只是想回家
they just want to be back home.
想回家遛狗  跟女朋友上床
They want to walk their dogs, screw their girlfriends,
去聚会喝酒狂欢
go to tailgate parties.
你是他的朋友
You're his friend.
他把你当亲儿子一样
Hell, he loves you like a son.
忘记我刚才说的话
Forget everything else that I've said
你扪心自问  我错了吗
and tell me from your gut that I'm wrong
马库斯选择的道路  真值得他们誓死追随吗
and his way is the right path for those men.
我的祖国在呼唤我
My nation is calling me,
而他却阻止我去回应
and he's not letting me answer the call.
也许你无法抉择  因为你不是那样的人
And maybe you can't decide. Maybe that's not who you are.
但我要你别挡我的路
But I'm asking you to stay out of the way.
因为不管怎样  事情都会发生的
Because this is happening, one way or the other.
秘密情报局参与一事会得到妥善处理
The secret service involvement will be clear.
我们的探员会悄悄地控制媒体
Our agents will quietly contain the press pool.
所有非关键人物都将被清理出白宫
All nonessential personnel will be vacated from the west wing.
我把你弄进去  完成你要做的事
I'll get you in, and you do what you have to do,
但对总统必须予以尊重
But the president will be treated with respect.
白宫的尊严也要予以维护
The dignity of the office will be preserved.
如果你的人心怀不轨  做出出格的事
Any of your boys get any ideas, go off book,
将会遭到坚决反击
they'll be pushed back.
我可不敢保证那之后会是什么样的结果
And I can't guarantee what happens after that.
我已经按你的要求做了
Look, I gave you what you asked for.
把剩下的钱给我
I want the rest of my money.
我该离开了
It's time for me to hit the road.
就这样吗
So that's it then?
你就打算拿着钱跑路吗
You're just gonna take the money and run?
是啊  差不多
Yeah, pretty much.
我能预感到哪里会成为危险地带
I know a kill zone when I see it.
不  别妄想了  不  不可能
No, no. Forget it！ No, forget it.
你疯了
You're out of your mind.
你们这些人
Are any of you even listening
没听到刚才说的话吗
to what's being said here out loud?
这是叛国
This is treason.
现在临阵退缩为时已晚  汤姆
It's a little late, Tom, to be getting cold feet.
上将  你已经成为计划的一部分了
Now, general, you're in this
不管你愿不愿意
whether you like it or not.
去死吧你
Go to hell！
你该在叫我来之前就处理好的
You should've gotten this together before you called me.
-别耍混  汤姆  -长官
- Don't be an ass, Tom. - Sir.
滚一边去
Stand aside！
来
Here.
你怎么会卷入这些纷争的
How did you get involved in all of this?
我发现了议员的阴谋
I found out what the senator was up to.
找他当面质问  而他
Confronted him about it, and he, uh...
从桌子下掏出一把枪  递给我
Slid a gun from his desk, handed it to me,
让我来做选择
and told me to make a choice.
那是我一生中最惊恐的时刻
The scariest moment of my life.
我是美国革命女儿会的一员
I'm a daughter of the American revolution.
我是
I was the, um...
国庆游行中的自由小姐
Junior Miss liberty in the 4th of July parade.
这一切都要成真了  不是吗
This is really happening, isn't it?
这一切成真  你功不可没
This is happening in large part because of you.
由于你的所为
Because of what you did,
我们才有机会让国家重回正轨
we have a chance to make things right again.
长官  是我  科泰兹
Sir, it's me--Cortez.
进来
Enter.
进来吧
Come in.
在看圣经吗  长官
The bible, sir?
它能让我放松
It relaxes me.
-想听我读一段吗  -请吧
- May I read you something? - Please.
饥渴慕义的人有福了
"Blessed are they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness,
因为他们必得饱足
for they shall be filled with the spirit of god."
为义受逼迫的人有福了
"And blessed are those that are persecuted for righteousness' sake,
因为天国是他们的
for theirs is the kingdom of heaven."
说得真好  长官
That's beautiful, sir.
在我看来  它说的是关于选择的问题
To me, it's about choice.
选择去做正确的事
Choosing to do the right thing
即使势单力孤
even though you are alone in that choice,
而不让未知之恐惧扰乱思绪
and not letting fear of the unknown cloud your thinking.
害怕一旦前路渺茫  无法看清
Fear that, when the path becomes too hard to see,
我们就会逃避回已知世界
we run back to what we know,
即使已知世界已经彻底崩坏  无法修复
even if what we know is broken beyond all repair.
他们派你来杀我吗
Did they send you here to kill me?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
那我们现在正面临这样的时刻
Then here we are.
选择的时刻
Time to choose.
当中情局第一次接触我时
When the CIA first approached me,
我刚大学毕业
I was finishing up college...
有巨额学生贷款需要偿还
Looking at a mountain of student loans.
之后我在海军入伍
I was already going into the navy
因为他们替我解决了一部分债务
'cause they'd picked up some of the tab.
中情局又给了我一笔钱
Langley was offering me a second paycheck
让我去处理一件可能永远不会发生的事
for something they said would never happen.
核潜艇艇长叛变
A nuclear sea captain going rogue.
我从没想过要当间谍
I never wanted to be a spy.
我只想做好本职工作
I just wanted to do my job well.
从这一切开始的那天起
From the day this started,
我一直都无所适从
I didn't know what I was supposed to do,
不知道该站在哪一边
who I was supposed to stand by...
该相信谁
who I believed in.
现在我已经做出决定了
I've made that decision.
我有很多敌人  科泰兹
I have enemies, Cortez.
我知道
I know.
但我不是你的敌人
But I am not one of them.
我们现在已经开诚布公了  下一步呢
Now that we looked up each other's skirts, what do we do,
把对方活活打死吗
beat each other to death?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
马库斯不能死  我要了解全部信息
Marcus isn't dying. I need to know everything--
计划是什么
What the plan is,
艇员们有什么想法
what the crew is thinking,
全部信息
everything.
欢迎来到底层的秘密世界
Welcome to the deep end of the pool.
马上给我传送过去
市长先生
Mr. Mayor,
有何贵干
How can I help you?
我来送礼的
I have a gift--
美国波旁酒
American bourbon.
小批量珍藏款
Small batch.
谢谢
Thank you.
你就不好奇我是从哪搞到这东西的吗
Are you not at least curious as to how I acquire such things?
那根本想都不用想
That doesn't require very much imagination.
也许吧
Yeah, perhaps not.
不管怎样  我在这座岛上没有摆不平的事
Either way, I am the man who gets things done on this island.
我认为马库斯・查普林
I am confident that Marcus Chaplin
才是圣玛丽娜岛的主人
is the man in charge of Sainte Marina.
那或许是你的想法
Well, you might think so.
你也许认为自己是因为政治原因而来
You might think that you are here for political reasons,
但并非如此
but you are mistaken.
你是冲着我和我的东西而来的
You're here for me and what I have to offer you.
其实  这个岛的价值远超你的想象
You see, there's more to this island than you can imagine.
相信我
Trust me.
我能给你无数个合适的理由
I can give you a billion reasons why.
给我一个就行
Just give me one.
稀土元素
Rare earth elements.
未来的石油
The oil of the future.
拿着这个样本
Take this sample.
去检测
Test it.
我相信你会非常高兴的
I'm sure you will be very pleased.
山姆
Sam.
你好
Hi.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  我没事
Yeah, I'm okay. I'm okay.
听着  我...
Look, I, um...
能让我先说一句吗
Can I... say something?
当然可以
Yeah, of course.
你们美国人经常取笑我们法国人
You Americans make fun of the French.
我们总在闹罢工  错过了摇滚乐的流行期
We're always on strike, we missed rock 'n' roll,
杰瑞・路易斯[美国艺人]
Jerry Lewis.
但是  我们法国人...
But, you know, we're not, um...
我不怕痛苦难受的感觉
I'm not scared about difficult feelings.
我不需要我在乎的人
I don't need the people I care about
时刻都开开心心  明明白白
to be happy all the time or clear
都清清楚楚地知道想要什么  或不想要什么
or know what they want or don't want.
也可以是一团乱的
It can be a mess.
我们喜欢乱乱的状态
We like messy.
如果你喜欢一团乱  那就找对人了
Well, if you like messy, I'm your guy.
你可以尽情取笑  但我不是在说笑
You're making fun of it, but I'm not.
我是你的朋友
I am your friend.
你无法忍受继续看到我
You can't stand seeing me.
彼此合不来  都没关系
It doesn't match. It's okay.
索菲  走不走
Sophie, are you coming?
知道伊迪丝・琵雅芙的一句法语箴言吗
Do you know this French saying from Edith Piaf,
无怨无悔
"Je ne regrette rein"?
不知道
No.
好吧
Okay.
很高兴见到你  副艇长
Good to see you, X.O.
很高兴见到你  长官
Good to see you, too, sir.
你没事吧
You okay?
克里斯蒂的事我不怪你
Look, I don't blame you for what happened to Christine.
我要你知道这一点
I want you to know that.
你想谈谈那事吗
You want to talk about it?
不想  想说的时候我会告诉你
No. I'll let you know when I do.
我今天那会儿很想念你
I missed you out there today.
事情变得复杂了吧
Thing got pretty hairy, didn't they?
以后要做的决定只会越来越艰难
Well, the decisions are not gonnt any easier.
我需要自己的帮手回来
I need my right hand back.
你要我回来  那我就回来
You want me back, then I'm back.